Guide to the Hanna House Collection SC0280
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Hanna House collection
1900-1995
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Hanna, Paul Robert
Hanna, Aurelia
SC0280
382 architectural drawings
5 album(s)
7 microfilm reel(s)
95 volume(s)
46.5 Linear Feet (95 volumes, 193 architectural drawings, 5 photograph albums, 7 microfilm reels)
Correspondence, blueprints, drawings, photographs, and other records relating to the planning, design and construction of the campus home of Professor and Mrs. Paul R. Hanna.
Biographical / Historical
In 1935, Paul and Jean Hanna commissioned Frank Lloyd Wright to design their home to be built on the Stanford University campus. Construction, begun in 1937, continued in four stages over 25 years. The house was the first structure in the world to use Frank Lloyd Wright's hexagonal grid system, which has subsequently been used widely in American architecture.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, blueprints, drawings, photographs, and other records relating to the planning, design and construction of the campus home of Professor and Mrs. Paul R. Hanna. The collection focuses on the Hanna's work with architect Frank Lloyd Wright extending from the initial planning of the house through later renovations.
Most of the correspondence and other records were arranged chronologically by the Hannas, with each document given a number that starts with the year of the document. These were then placed in 3-ring binders. There is a detailed index to the first 53 volumes, which is available in a separate binder. Make note of the document numbers you wish to see and then consult the listing here to find the volume number. You will need to complete a paging slip for each volume you wish to consult.
Accession 2008-247 is a photograph album of the March 1, 1977 Nissan Motor Corporation visit to the Hanna House. After ownership of the house was transferred to Stanford University, the Nissan Motor Company provided a $500,000 endowment towards its maintenance.
Access to Collection
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Existence and Location of Copies
The seven microfilm rolls record three separate portions of the collection:
1. Archives: Microfilm Rolls Nos.1 - 5.
Fifty-three (53) binder volumes of correspondence with Frank Lloyd Wright and others, telegrarns, telephone notes, contracts, building specifications, financial transactions, and other items, covering a half-century from 1930 through 1981. Circa 6,000 pages of documents record the story of Mr. Wright's designing of the project, tile construction of several buildings - accomplished in five phases, the role of Stanford University, the public and architects' interest in the project, an evaluation by the clients, and many related aspects.
Each item in the Archives (Vols. 1 - 53, microfilmed on Rolls 1 - 5) is numbered consecutively for each year. To illustrate: page number 360021 is read as follows, the first two numbers of the series (36) represent the year in which the document originated (1936); the last two numbers (21) indicate that this document is the 21st item prepared in the year; 790305 will be the 305th document prepared in 1979; etc.
2. Photographs: Microfilm Roll No.6.
Five albums of photographs of the original site, stages of construction, exterior and interior shots, furniture and fUrnishings. Over 500 photos taken by professional architectural photographers and by the clients.
3. Drawings. Microfilm Roll No.7.
184 sketches and drawings (mostly blueprints) by Frank Lloyd Wright, consultants, and the Hannas.
Other Finding Aids
Index to Microfilm: http://purl.stanford.edu/nd730bn4620
Related Materials
Darwin D. Martin Papers (M0355): This extremely rich resource includes over 200 letters handwritten or typed by Wright and over 2000 letters addressed to him. There are also drafts of manuscripts, pamphlets, a host of financial and legal documents, a few· photographs, and 28 drawings, blueprints and sketches by Wright. Stanford purchased the Martin materials jointly with the State University of New York at Buffalo in June, 1982, with the agreement that the original materials be divided equally between the two institutions, Buffalo receiving those papers from 1888-1914 and Stanford holding those from 1915-1979. Eacn university in turn supplied the other with copies of their originals, thus maintaining the integrity of the collections. Both Buffalo and Stanford made subsequent and independent purchases of Martin materials designed to enhance their previous acquisitions in 1983. Stanford obtained some 500 letters, contracts, and other documents highlighting Wright's financial and legal indebtedness to Darwin D. Martin during the years 1910-1930.
George D. Sturges collection (M0494): 8 letters dating from 1941 and a set of photographic negatives by Robert Imandt of the Sturges house in Brentwood Heights, California, 1939-1941. The collection nonetheless provides valuable insights into the "skyway" house and Wright's reservations about his Taliesin apprentices.
Victoria Schuck papers (M1117): This resource details the history of a project for a house for Dr. Victoria Schuck in South Hadly, Massachusetts from 1955-70 and includes 27 letters, 3 color-pencil drawings, and 4 blueprints showing the initial and revised floor plans and elevations.
For more information see: http://purl.stanford.edu/nd730bn4620.
Architecture, Domestic -- California -- Stanford.; Architecture -- California -- Stanford.; Architecture.; aesthetics, design; Design.; Architecture -- California -- 20th century.; Architecture, Modern -- 20th century.; Architecture, Domestic -- California; Hanna, Jean Shuman; Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1867-1959; Hanna, Paul Robert; Hanna, Aurelia
- Building documentation, 1935-1986
  - Hanna House volumes
    - Volume 01 - Documents 350001-360061 (indexed), 1935 May-1936 Jun; 1 volume(s) (Box 1)
    - Volume 02 - Documents 360062-3360122 (indexed), 1936 Jul-Dec; 1 volume(s) (Box 1)
    - Volume 03 - Documents 370001-370162 (indexed), 1937 Jan-Apr; 1 volume(s) (Box 1)
    - Volume 04 - Documents 370163-370298 (indexed), 1937 May-Dec; 1 volume(s) (Box 1)
    - Volume 05 - Documents 370299-370370, Construction financial records, (indexed), 1937; 1 volume(s) (Box 1)
    - Volume 06 - Documents 370371-370418, Construction financial records, (indexed), 1937; 1 volume(s) (Box 2)
    - Volume 07 - Documents 370419-370599, Subcontractors and suppliers (Aeroshade through Glass) (indexed), 1 volume(s) (Box 2)
    - Volume 08 - Documents 370600-370840, Subcontractors and suppliers (Hardware through Steel) (indexed), 1937; 1 volume(s) (Box 2)
    - Volume 09 - Documents 380001-390024 (indexed), 1938 Jan-1939 Dec; 1 volume(s) (Box 2)
    - Volume 10 - Documents 400001-440002 (indexed), 1940 Jan - 1944 Jul; 1 volume(s) (Box 3)
    - Volume 11 - Documents 450001-480006 (indexed), 1945 Jan - 1948 Nov; 1 volume(s) (Box 3)
    - Volume 12 - Documents 490001-500094 (indexed), March 1949-December 1950; 1 volume(s) (Box 3)
    - Volume 13 - Documents 500095-500197, Subcontractors and suppliers (Appliances through tools) (indexed), 1950; 1 volume(s) (Box 3)
    - Volume 14 - Documents 510001-540037 (indexed), January 1951-August 1954; 1 volume(s) (Box 3)
    - Volume 15 - Documents 550001-560025 (indexed), March 1955-December 1956; 1 volume(s) (Box 4)
    - Volume 16 - Documents 570001-570176 (indexed), 1957; 1 volume(s) (Box 4)
    - Volume 17 - Documents 570177-570372, Subcontractors and suppliers (Appliances through Hardware) (indexed), 1957; 1 volume(s) (Box 4)
    - Volume 18 - Documents 570373-570492, Subcontractors and suppliers (Landscaping through Window washing (indexed), 1957; 1 volume(s) (Box 4)
    - Volume 19 - Documents 580001-580164 (indexed), 1958; 1 volume(s) (Box 4)
    - Volume 20 - Documents 590001-590050 (indexed), 1959; 1 volume(s) (Box 5)
    - Volume 21 - Documents 600001-600155 (indexed), 1960; 1 volume(s) (Box 5)
    - Volume 22 - Documents 610001-610140 (indexed), January-October 1961; 1 volume(s) (Box 5)
    - Volume 23 - Documents 620001-620130 (indexed), 1962; 1 volume(s) (Box 5)
    - Volume 24 - Documents 630001-630157 (indexed), 1963 Jan-Mar; 1 volume(s) (Box 5)
    - Volume 25 - Documents 630158-630244 (indexed), 1963 Apr-Dec; 1 volume(s) (Box 6)
    - Volume 26 - Documents 640001-640084 (indexed), 1964; 1 volume(s) (Box 6)
    - Volume 27 - Documents 650001-650062 (indexed), 1965; 1 volume(s) (Box 6)
    - Volume 28 - Documents 660001-660085 (indexed), 1966; 1 volume(s) (Box 6)
    - Volume 29 - AIA plaque, Documents 590051-670049 (indexed), 1959-1967; 1 volume(s) (Box 6)
    - Volume 30 - Documents 670001-670047 (indexed), 1967; 1 volume(s) (Box 7)
    - Volume 31 - Documents 680001-690063 (indexed), 1968-1969; 1 volume(s) (Box 7)
    - Volume 32 - Documents 700001-710062 (indexed), 1970-1971; 1 volume(s) (Box 7)
    - Volume 33 - Documents 720001-720091 (indexed), 1972; 1 volume(s) (Box 7)
    - Volume 34 - Documents 730001-730107 (indexed), 1973; 1 volume(s) (Box 7)
    - Volume 35 - Documents 740001-740174 (indexed), 1974; 1 volume(s) (Box 8)
    - Volume 36 - Documents 750001-750120 (indexed), 1975 Jan-May; 1 volume(s) (Box 8)
    - Volume 37 - Documents 750121-750191 (indexed), 1975 Jun-Oct; 1 volume(s) (Box 8)
    - Volume 38 - Documents 750192-750278 (indexed), 1975 Nov-Dec; 1 volume(s) (Box 8)
    - Volume 39 - Documents 760001-760131 (indexed), 1976; 1 volume(s) (Box 8)
    - Volume 40 - Documents 770001-770117 (indexed), 1977 Jan-May; 1 volume(s) (Box 9)
    - Volume 41 - Documents 770118-770251E (indexed), 1977 Jun-Aug; 1 volume(s) (Box 9)
    - Volume 42 - Documents 770252-770351 (indexed), 1977 Sep-Dec; 1 volume(s) (Box 9)
    - Volume 43 - Documents 780001-780182 (indexed), 1978 Jan-Oct; 1 volume(s) (Box 9)
    - Volume 44 - Documents 780183-780285 (indexed), 1978 Nov-Dec; 1 volume(s) (Box 9)
    - Volume 45 - Documents 790001-790111B (indexed), 1979 Jan-Apr; 1 volume(s) (Box 10)
    - Volume 46 - Documents 790112-790226 (indexed), 1979 May-Aug; 1 volume(s) (Box 10)
    - Volume 47 - Documents 790227-790313 (indexed), 1979 Sep-Oct; 1 volume(s) (Box 10)
    - Volume 48 - Documents 790314-790435 (indexed), 1979 Nov-Dec; 1 volume(s) (Box 10)
    - Volume 49 - Documents 800001-800096 (indexed), 1980 Jan-Mar; 1 volume(s) (Box 10)
    - Volume 50 - Documents 800097-800272 (indexed), 1980 Apr-Jul; 1 volume(s) (Box 11)
    - Volume 51 - Documents 800273-800370 (indexed), 1980 Aug-Dec; 1 volume(s) (Box 11)
    - Volume 52 - Documents 810002-810179 (indexed), 1981 Jan-Jun; 1 volume(s) (Box 11)
    - Volume 52A - Lecture before Stanford Historical Society, 1980 Jun 4; 1 volume(s) (Box 11)
    - Volume 53 - Documents 810181-810301 (indexed), 1981 Jul-Dec; 1 volume(s) (Box 12)
    - Volume 53A, 1981 Mar-Dec; 1 volume(s) (Box 12)
    - Volume 54 - Documents 820001-820119, 1982 Jan-Apr; 1 volume(s) (Box 12)
    - Volume 55 - Documents 820120-820178, 1982 May; 1 volume(s) (Box 12)
    - Volume 56 - Documents 820179-820231, 1982 Jun-Jul; 1 volume(s) (Box 13)
    - Volume 57 - Documents 820232-820304, 1982 Aug-Dec; 1 volume(s) (Box 13)
    - Volume 57A, 1982 Jan-Jun; 1 volume(s) (Box 13)
    - Volume 57B, 1982 Jun 14-1982 Jun; 1 volume(s) (Box 13)
    - Volume 57C, 1982 Jul-Dec; 1 volume(s) (Box 13)
    - Volume 58 - Documents 830001-830115, not indexed, 1983 Jan-May; 1 volume(s) (Box 14)
    - Volume 59 - Documents 830116-830151, not indexed, 1983 Jun-Aug; 1 volume(s) (Box 14)
    - Volume 60 - Documents 830142-830183, not indexed, 1983 Sep-Dec; 1 volume(s) (Box 14)
    - Volume 61 - Documents 840001-840097B, not indexed, 1984 Jan-Jun; 1 volume(s) (Box 14)
    - Volume 62 - Documents 840098-840191, not indexed, 1984 Jul-Dec; 1 volume(s) (Box 14)
    - Volume 63 - Documents 850001-850082, not indexed, 1985 Jul-Dec; 1 volume(s) (Box 15)
    - Volume 64 - Documents 850083-850137, not indexed, 1985 Jul-Dec; 1 volume(s) (Box 15)
    - Volume 65 - Documents, not indexed, 1986 Jan-Dec; 1 volume(s) (Box 15)
  - Wright, Frank Lloyd volumes, 1914-1985
    - Volume 1, 1914 Aug - 1955 Nov; 1 volume(s) (Box 16)
    - Volume 2, 1956 Feb-1958 Dec; 1 volume(s) (Box 16)
    - Volume 3, 1959 Jan - 1960 Dec; 1 volume(s) (Box 16)
    - Volume 4, 1961 Jan - 1964 Oct; 1 volume(s) (Box 16)
    - Volume 5, 1965 Mar - 1969 Dec; 1 volume(s) (Box 17)
    - Volume 6, 1970 Jan - 1974 Nov; 1 volume(s) (Box 17)
    - Volume 7, 1975 Mar - 1977 Dec; 1 volume(s) (Box 17)
    - Volume 8, 1978 Feb-Nov; 1 volume(s) (Box 17)
    - Volume 9, 1979; 1 volume(s) (Box 18)
    - Volume 10, 1980; 1 volume(s) (Box 18)
    - Documents (not numbered, not indexed), 1936-1982; 1 volume(s) (Box 18)
    - Documents (not numbered, not indexed), 1983-1984; 1 volume(s) (Box 18)
    - Documents (not numbered, not indexed), 1985; 1 volume(s) (Box 18)
  - Volumes by individual title, 1937-1986
    - Frank Lloyd Wright/Partial Listing, 1937; 1 volume(s) (Box 19)
    - Frank Lloyd Wright/Partial Record of Gifts to Stanford University - Documents 630253-770352, 1963-1981; 1 volume(s) (Box 19)
    - Frank Lloyd Wright Taliesin Square Papers #1-17, 1941-1953; 1 volume(s) (Box 19)
    - Frank Lloyd Wright/Hanna House Nissan Gift to Stanford, 1 volume(s) (Box 19)
    - Frank Lloyd Wright General-A, 1986; 1 volume(s) (Box 20)
    - Frank Lloyd Wright General-B, 1986; 1 volume(s) (Box 20)
    - Frank Lloyd Wright General Catalogs, 1 volume(s) (Box 20)
    - Frank Lloyd Wright/Hanna House Board of Governors, 1 volume(s) (Box 20)
- Photographs, 1900-1981
  - Volume I, 1935-1942; 1 volume(s) (Box 21)
    Scope and Contents
    Original site on Coutts Farm; Hanna's building lot; Construction; Exteriors and Interiors; Inspecting failure of original copper roof
  - Volume II, 1950-1977; 1 volume(s) (Box 21)
    Construction of workshop and guest house; other photographs, arranged chronologically.
  - Volume III, 1900-1962; 1 volume(s) (Box 21)
    Wright, Frank Lloyd; Building site; Exteriors and interiors; Workshop; Aerial views
  - Volume IV, 1960-1980; 1 volume(s) (Box 21)
    Plaques; Exteriors and interiors; Fire; Fountain, cascade, pool; Setting Frank Lloyd Wright Urn from Tokyo Imperial Hotel; Autumn and Winter; Furniture designed by Wright, Frank Lloyd; Visit of Japanese architects; Chess sets; Miscellaneous
  - Volume V, 1975-1981; 1 volume(s) (Box 21)
    Exteriors and interiors; Nissan gift to HHH; Exteriors and interiors; Paul R. Hanna
- Architectural drawings, 1936-1963
  - Perspective sketch of exterior, 1936; 1; 1 diazo print; 22 x 29 inches (Box Sa12)
    Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1867-1959
  - Perspective sketch of exterior (same as Num. 001), 1936; 2; 1 Photostat negative; 17 x 24 inches (Box Sa12)
  - Perspective sketch of exterior (same as Num. 001), 1936; 3; 1 Photostat copy; 17 x 24 inches (Box Sa12)
  - Plot plan, initialled and dated by Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1936 Nov 11; 5; 1 blueprint; 36 x 42 inches (Box Sa15)
  - Plan for concrete mat and brickwork, initialled and dated by Wright, Frank Lloyd (with field notations by builder), 1936 Nov 11; 7; 1 blueprint; 36 x 42 inches (Box Sa20)
  - Floor plan, initialled and dated by Frank Lloyd Wright; (marked "REVISED PLAN" and "NEW 1-10-37" in red pencil), 1936 Nov 11, 1937 Jan 10; 9; 1 blueprint; 36 x 42 inches (Box Sa18)
  - Illumination plan - sheet 1; signed and dated by Wolf, 1937 Mar 23; 12; 1 blueprint; 22 x 27 inches
    Wolf, Carl F., elec. engineer
  - Plan of mat and tunnel - sheet 2; signed by Wolf, 1937 Mar 23; 13; 1 blueprint; 22 x 27 inches (Box Sa12)
  - Floor plan and details for lighting and power - sheet 3; signed by Wolf, 1937 Mar 23; 14; 1 blueprint; 22 x 27 inches (Box Sa12)
  - Continuation of floor plan and details for lighting and power - sheet 4; signed by Wolf, 1937 Mar 23; 15; 1 blueprint; 22 x 27 inches (Box Sa12)
  - Details and position of walls over typical floor unit, flush ceiling light details; section thru playroom to boys BR - sheet 5; signed and dated by Wolf, 1937 Mar 22; 16; 1 blueprint; 22 x 27 inches (Box Sa12)
  - Revised floor plan of Hanna House showing change in terraces; dated and initialed by FLW, 17
  - Exterior elevations (3), initialled by Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1936 Nov 11; 19; 1 blueprint; 36 x 42 inches (Box Sa17)
  - Electrogas schematic of 3-zone heating system, dated, prepared by Electrogas, 1937 Feb 12; 28; 1 blueprint; 17 x 24 inches (Box Sa12)
    Electrogas Furnace and Mfg. Co.
  - Warm air ducts and registers sizes, dated, prepared by Electrogas, 1937 Feb 2; 29; 1 blueprint; 17 x 24 inches (Box Sa12)
  - Framing plan for flat roofs and decks, initialled and dated by Wright, Frank Lloyd (date illegible); (This plan shows building cross-section reference lines.), 30; 1 blueprint; 36 x 36 inches (Box Sa18)
  - Framing plan for pitched roofs, initialled and dated by Wright, Frank Lloyd (date illegible), 31; 1 blueprint; 36 x 36 inches (Box Sa18)
  - Section A-A thru living room, laboratory, bath & bedroom, initialled and dated by Wright, Frank Lloyd (date illegible), 32; 1 blueprint; 24.5 x 42 inches (Box Sa18)
  - Section B-B thru living room and Section D-D thru playroom, bypass and bedroom, initialled and dated by Wright, Frank Lloyd (date illegible); Section mislabelled E-E corrected in ink to read D-D., 33; 1 blueprint; 31.5 x 42 inches (Box Sa18)
  - Section G-G thru living room, entry and sanctum, undated; 35; 1 blueprint; 21 x 36 inches (Box Sb12)
  - Section H-H thru carport, servant's room & guest bath, initialled and dated (illegible) by Wright, Frank Lloyd, 36; 1 blueprint; 21 x 40 inches (Box Sb12)
  - Main retaining wall and mat, initialled and dated (illegible) by Wright, Frank Lloyd; (Pencil notations on print showing brick veneer ties and flower box modifications.), 37; 1 blueprint; 20 x 31.5 inches (Box Sa12)
  - Perforated boards, showing details of lantern between playroom and bedroom and perforated boards over entry, initialled and dated (illegible) by Wright, Frank Lloyd, 38; 1 blueprint; 33 x 42 inches (Box Sa17)
  - Full size detail of clerestory windows, initialled and dated (illegible) by Wright, Frank Lloyd, 39; 1 blueprint; 31 x 36 inches (Box Sa17)
  - Details of chimney and basement, initialled and dated by Wright, Frank Lloyd; (This appears to incorporated studies from No. 40.), 1937 Jan 30; 41; 1 blueprint; 24 x 42 inches (Box Sa18)
  - Sanctum fireplace and chimney, initialled by Wright, Frank Lloyd, undated; 42; 1 blueprint; 19 x 42 inches (Box Sb12)
  - Full size detail of sloping roof fascia at exterior wall plate, initialled and dated (illegible) by Wright, Frank Lloyd, 43; 1 blueprint; 29 x 36 inches (Box Sa18)
  - Full size detail of trellis and full size detail of where sloped roof joins roof, initialled and dated (illegible) by Wright, Frank Lloyd, 44; 1 blueprint; 34 x 36 inches (Box Sa18)
  - Full size detail of flat roof facsia at exterior wall plate, initialled and dated (illegible) by Wright, Frank Lloyd, 45; 1 blueprint; 24 x 36 inches (Box Sb12)
  - Skylight over laundry, undated; 47; 1 blueprint; 21 x 42 inches (Box Sb12)
  - Lantern, initialled by Wright, Frank Lloyd, 49; 1 blueprint; 19.5 x 42 inches (Box Sb12)
  - Full size details for upper laboratory and baths, initialled by Wright, Frank Lloyd, 50; 1 blueprint; 35 x 42 inches (Box Sa17)
  - Planting diagram; entrance and wall layout, initialled by Wright, Frank Lloyd, undated; 51; 1 blueprint; 36 x 42 inches (Box Sa17)
  - Full size detail of doors in hexagon and to basement and full size detail of doors in daughter's room, undated; 52; 1 sepia transparency; 29.5 x 36 inches (Box Sa17)
    Scope and Contents note
    Appears to be an in-progress print showing development of details finalized in No. 52a.
  - Full size details of all typical jambs, initialled by Wright, Frank Lloyd; (Incorporates and supersedes No. 52.), Illegible; 53; 1 blueprint; 33 x 41 inches (Box Sa17)
  - Full size details of muntin on all sash, initialled by Wright, Frank Lloyd, Illegible; 54; 1 blueprint; 19.5 x 42 inches (Box Sb12)
  - Delivery box, undated; 55; 1 blueprint; 20.5 x 42 inches (Box Sb12)
  - Sash schedule (Red pencil dimensions and corrections on print), undated; 56; 1 blueprint; 23 x 41.5 inches (Box Sa16)
  - Full size details showing use of outside sash with the jamb; initialled by Wright, Frank Lloyd, 57; 1 blueprint; 33 x 36 inches (Box Sa16)
  - Sash folding on track; initialled by Wright, Frank Lloyd, 58; 1 blueprint; 33.5 x 42 inches
  - Sheet No. 1: Hanna Res., H.P. Turner, Foreman; (Millwork shop drawing), undated; 59; 1 blueprint; 72 x 24 inches
    Pacific Manufacturing Company
  - Sheet No. 2: Hanna Res., H.P. Turner, Foreman; (Millwork shop drawing), undated; 60; 1 blueprint; 36 x 24 inches
  - Sheet No. 4: Hanna Res., H.P. Turner, Foreman; (Millwork shop drawing), undated; 61; 1 blueprint; 72 x 24 inches
  - Sheet No. 5: Hanna Res., H.P. Turner, Foreman; (Millwork shop drawing), undated; 62; 1 blueprint; 59 x 24 inches (Box Sb11)
  - Sheet No. 6: Hanna Res., H.P. Turner, Foreman; (Millwork shop drawing), undated; 63; 1 blueprint; 49 x 20 inches (Box Sa20)
  - Completion of ventilator, initialled by Wright, Frank Lloyd, undated; 64; 1 blueprint; 13 x 15.5 inches (Box Sa12)
  - Completion of ventilator; (Same as No. 64, except has dimensions added in pencil), undated; 65; 1 diazo print; 12.5 x 15 inches (Box Sa13)
  - Easy chair, ottoman, and floor cushion details; (Includes drawings by Wright, Frank Lloyd; appears to be an in-progress print), undated; 66; 1 sepia transparency; 24 x 36 inches (Box Sa13)
  - Easy chair, ottoman, and floor cushion details, initialled by Wright, Frank Lloyd; (Finalized version of No. 66), 1937; 67; 1 blackline diazo print; 24 x 36 inches (Box Sb12)
  - Red lacquer hexagonal table, undated; 68; 1 blueprint; 16 x 21 inches (Box Sa13)
  - Furniture sheet no. 1, including living rm. cabinet work, couches, initialled by Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1937; 69; 1 blueprint; 36 x 42 inches (Box Sa16)
  - Furniture sheet no. 2, including laboratory, playroom and dining table, initialled and dated by Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1937 Jul 30; 70; 1 blueprint; 36 x 42 inches (Box Sa16)
  - Furniture sheet no. 3, including bedrooms and sanctum, initialled by Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1937 Jul 30; 71; 1 blueprint; 36 x 42 inches (Box Sa17)
  - Straight chair, for dining table, initialled and dated by Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1937 Jul 30; 72; 1 blackline diazo print; 22 x 36 inches (Box Sa13)
  - Screen between laboratory and living room, initialled by Wright, Frank Lloyd, illegible; 73; 1 blueprint; 36 x 42 inches (Box Sa19)
  - Fireplace fixture and bookplate, initialled by Wright, Frank Lloyd, undated; 74; 1 (Box Sa13)
  - Sanctum fireplace spit, incl. tools, initialled by Wright, Frank Lloyd, illegible; 75; 1 blackline diazo print; 20.5 x 36 inches (Box Sb12)
  - Barbeque exhedera, initialled by Wright, Frank Lloyd, undated; 76; 1 blueprint; 13 x 35 inches (Box Sb12)
  - Garden pool, initialled by Wright, Frank Lloyd, undated; 77; 1 blueprint; 21 x 36 inches (Box Sa13)
  - Garden wall; (Appears to be a program print, later supersided by No. 77), undated; 78; 1 sepia transparency; 21.5 x 36 inches (Box Sb13)
  - Garden wall, initialled by Wright, Frank Lloyd, undated; 79; 1 blueprint; 36 x 42 inches (Box Sa16)
  - Carpet layout, undated; 80; 1 blueprint; 20 x 42 inches (Box Sb13)
  - Revised roofing diagram; (scheme for new copper roof with batten seams), 1940; 81; 1 diazo print; 30.5 x 36 inches (Box Sa16)
  - Addition to house for Dr. Hanna, floor plan initialled and dated by Wright, Frank Lloyd (Preliminary plan with handwritten note by Frank Lloyd Wright re: extension into adjacent property), 1946 Sep 15; 82; 1 blueprint; 29 x 28 inches (Box Sb13)